Discarded artificial satellites.
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
（ナレーション）
使い捨てられた人工衛星
シャトルが切り離したタンク
ステーション建造時に出た廃棄物
Refuse generated during
space station construction.
This trash, space debris, circles the Earth
at speeds approaching 8 kilometers per second.
これら 宇宙のゴミ
スペースデブリは―
秒速８キロメートル近い速度で
地球の周りを回っています
そんなデブリが
宇宙船とぶつかれば―
Should this debris collide with a spacecraft,
it could result in a terrible accident.
大きな事故に つながりかねません
For this reason, mankind has been confronted
by the necessity of collecting this debris.
そこで人々は デブリを
回収する必要に迫られました
2075年―
This is a story of 2075, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
これは 宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
Passengers, may we have
your attention please.
（タナベ）はあ～
Don't you think this subtle
floating sensation is great?
なんか この微妙な
フワフワ感が面白いですね
（フィー）
無重力でもなく １Ｇでもなく？
You mean how it's not zero-G,
and not one-G, either?
はい
なんか妖精にでもなった気分です
Yes, ma'am! It feels like I've turned
into a fairy or something!
（ハチマキ）
ケッ 何が妖精だよ
Fairy, my ass.
More like a devil.
…ていうより悪魔
せめて 小悪魔って言ってください
At least make it "cute little imp."
あっ 天使でもいいですよ
Oh! "Angel" would be
fine, too.
であっ うわあーっ
（ハチマキ）ハハハッ
そら見ろ 堕天使が
Serves ya right,
you fallen angel!
先輩
笑ってないで助けてくださいよ
Senpai, stop laughing at me
and help me up...
Well, I'll let you get
Tanabe squared away.
じゃ タナベのことは頼んだ
I have to pop in for a quick visit
to Third Division.
私は 第３事業部に
顔 出さなくちゃならないから
ん？
あっ ありが…
Thank y...
ハハハハ… バーカ
Moron!
何 子供みたいな
意地悪してんですか
What are you, a kid?
Don't tease me like that!
You're the one who's a kid!
Look at you, making such a big deal out of this!
（ハチマキ）
お前のほうが子供だってえの
はしゃぎやがって
（タナベ）キィー 先輩だって
ガイドに赤丸 付けてたくせに
（フィー）ハァ…
Big talk from a guy who made all those
red circles in his guide book!
（タナベ）キィー 先輩だって
ガイドに赤丸 付けてたくせに
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪幾千の朝に
♪光が向かう場所へ
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
（ハチマキ）
今いる所は―
The level we're on now has various companies
and government administration buildings.
Phase 6
The Lunar Flying Squirrels
いろんな会社や
官公庁がある
Shopping centers and residential areas
are below that.
商業施設や住宅街は
その下だ
要するに
上のほうがお偉いさんで―
In otherwords, the upper crust are up top,
and the lower classes live below.
下々の者は 地下のほうってわけだ
そういや お前
どこに 家 借りたんだ？
Speaking of which, where's
the place you're renting?
課長が借りてくれたので
Well, the Chief rented it for me,
so I don't...
あった
Here it is!
アルノ地区の３の14 ４号室です
Arnould Area, 3-14. Room 4.
だったら
途中まで ついてってやるよ
In that case, I'll walk you partway there.
We're headed in the same direction.
行き先 同じだからな
You're renting a place in
Arnould Area, too, Senpai?
先輩もアルノ地区に
家 借りてるんですか？
No, I have an appointment
at the Grand Hotel. It's nearby.
いや
近くのグランホテルで待ち合わせ
課長に頼まれて 届け物だ
The Chief asked me
to deliver this.
（サリバン）
早すぎたんじゃないか？
Aren't we early? We still have
more than two hours.
まだ ２時間以上ある
（チッタ）
着付けって 結構 時間かかるのよ
It takes a while
to get dressed.
Besides, I want to have some time
to unwind after that.
それに 着付けてから
落ち着く余裕は欲しいじゃない？
（案内係）いらっしゃいませ
Welcome to the hotel.
ああ 予約したサリバンですけど
Thanks.
We have a reservation under "Sullivan."
（案内係）
サリバン様 承っております
Ah, Sullivan-sama.
We've been expecting you.
では お荷物のお預かりを…
I'll see to your luggage.
You don't need to go to all that trouble.
（サリバン）
そんな気張らなくてもなあ
I'd like to get changed first.
（チッタ）
着付けを済ませておきたいんですが
Of course.
This boy hardly seems like the formal wear type.
向こうだって
大した風采じゃないぞ
（フィー）
第２事業部のカーマイケルです
I'm Carmichael, Second Division.
I'm here about the end-of-month balance
sheet for the Graveyard Orbit.
墓場軌道の月末決算に…
（チャド）フィー！
- Fee!
（フィー）
ん？ ああ こっちに配転？
You transferred here?
I just couldn't keep up with
those lifetime workers.
生え抜きさんには かなわないよ
小さい会社でやってきた俺には
数字も責任も大きすぎた
For a guy from a small
company like me, the numbers and responsibility
were too much to handle.
（フィー）うーん
（チャド）ドルフは どうしてる？
What's Dolf up to
these days?
（フィー）
相変わらずの仕事人間よ
He's still a man
who lives for his job.
（チャド）あいつは すごいよな
That man
is amazing.
テクノーラみたいな大きなとこでも
事業部長として立派にやってる
He's doing so well
for himself.
He's even a department manager
at a big company like Technora.
Rumor has it that he's in line for
the board of directors, too, right?
取締役も近いって うわさだろう？
さあね うわさ話には疎いんだ
I wouldn't know. I don't really
keep up with the gossip.
すごいよな あいつは
昔から すごかったもんな
That man is something else. He always
was amazing, even in the old days.
俺なんかとは違うんだよな
The two of us are like
night and day...
ああ よかったら食事でもどう？
昔話でもしようよ
Say, why don't we get some dinner or
something? We can talk about old times.
ウヘエ…
（工事の音）
（男性）てめえ 俺のいねえ間に
また連れ込みやがったな
You bitch! You brought a man home
while I was away again, didn't you?!
If you don't like it, try
being at home for once!
（女性）それが嫌なら
ちっとは 家(うち)にいなさいよ
（男性）何だ ごらあ
- What did you say?!
Shut up,
you deadbeat!
（女性）
うるっさいわね この駄目男
（男性）ヒヒヒ… あっ
（タナベ）へ？
ヒエー ヘッヘー
着いたぞ お前の新しい家
Well, here we are.
Welcome to your new home.
（タナベ）ええ？
（ハチマキ）じゃあな
See ya.
（タナベ）
ええっ もう行っちゃうんですか？
You're leaving already?!
言ったろ？ ４時にホテルだって
I told you, I have to be
at the hotel by four.
うわあっ
（ハチマキ）んっ
（タナベ）うーん…
（ハチマキ）ほら見ろ
普通のとこじゃないか
See, what did I tell you?
The place is perfectly normal.
Since you've already come this far, walk me
the rest of the way to my room, okay?
ここまで来たんですから
部屋まで ついてきてくださいよ
You have plenty of time
before 4 o'clock, so...
４時までなら…
（食器の鳴る音）
（タナベ）えっ？
（ハチマキ）ん？
（食器の鳴る音）
ほ… ほら なんか変ですよ ここ
S-See? There's something
weird about this place!
Don't let it get to you, It's just
a strange door chime, that's all.
気にすんな
ちょっと変わったドアチャイムだよ
What about
those, then?!
じゃあ あれは？
（ハチマキ）あ？ まき… びし？
Ninja... caltrops?
（小源太(こげんた)）そのとおり！
（タナベ･ハチマキ）えっ？
Exactly right!
Your eyes are indeed sharp,
my good visitors!
（小源太）
よくぞ 見破った 来訪者どもよ
まずは あっぱれと褒めておこう
First, allow me to offer you
my compliments.
Um, Tanabe?
What's that look like to you?
（ハチマキ）
なあ タナベ あれ 何に見える？
（タナベ）何…
忍者以外の何に見えるんですか？
What do you mean?
What else could he be but a ninja?
（小源太）
おひけえなすってえ
Hark and attend
my words!
I am a Koga ninja.
I am known
as Kogenta of the Mist.
拙者 甲賀(こうが)の忍び
霞(かすみ)の小源太と申す者でござんす
ほらほら
本人も ああ言ってますし
Hey, you hear that?
He says so, too!
“おひけえなすって”は
忍びじゃねえだろ
It wasn't ninjas who used to say
"Hark and attend my words"...
キエーッ とわっ
とうっ！
伊賀(いが) 十字撃ち
Iga cross attack!
（タナベ･ハチマキ）ええっ！？
（タナベ）先輩 本物ですよ
Senpai! He's the real thing!
Yeah, a real head case.
ああ 本物の変態だな
逃げろ！
（タナベ）えっ
Let's get outta here!
（ハチマキ）冗談だろ おあっ
（タナベ）うええっ
You gotta be
kidding me!
（小源太）
カッカッカッカッ… クアッハ～
よかったな タナベ
楽しそうなとこじゃないか
Good for you, Tanabe!
Looks like you've got some fun neighbors!
（タナベ）どこがですか！
What makes you
say that?!
Well, I'll let you
get acquainted!
じゃあ 俺は これで
How can you be so
irresponsible, Senpai?!
（タナベ）無責任ですよ 先輩！
うっ…
（紅右近(くれないうこん)）忍法 壁走り！
Ninpo Wall-walking Technique!
（タナベ）また変なのが出たー
Another weirdo showed up!
（ハチマキ）こっちだ
（タナベ）うっ うう…
This way!
（太郎坊(たろうぼう)）
逃しはしないでごわす
There is no escape
from us!
（ハチマキ）げえっ
（タナベ）ええっ
Have a taste of the astonishing
Human Throwing Star!
（太郎坊）
食らいませ 驚愕(きょうがく)人間手裏剣！
（三次(さんじ)）如意棒！
Iron cudgel!
だああーっ
Finishing move!
Flying Fans!
（幻之丞(げんのじょう)）必殺 扇の舞！
はいはい はいはい はいはい
Hup hup hup hup!
はいはい はいはい はいはい…
Pretend you don't
see him!
（ハチマキ）
見ないふり 見ないふり
（地雷也(じらいや)）
いでよ がま五右衛門(ごえもん)
Come forth,
Gamagoemon!
（人形）ア～
（ハチマキ）
だあ 知らんぷり 知らんぷり
Ignore him, ignore him!
（チュン）
アチョー チョチョチョー チョー
That's strange, it looks like
some of them aren't ninjas!
（タナベ）なんか忍者じゃない人も
混じってるみたいですけど
Seeing ninjas running around in
the first place is what's strange!
（ハチマキ）
忍者がいる時点でおかしいだろ
（課長）ええっ 何だって？
Huh? What was that?
だから タナベのアパートだよ
I'm talking about Tanabe's apartment!
You rented it out, didn't you?!
課長が借りたんだろ？
ああ もう…
（課長）ああ
日本人に おすすめって言うから
That's right.
It came highly recommended for Japanese people.
（ハチマキ）おすすめじゃねえよ！
- Recommended, my ass!
ああ もう…
（課長）ハッちゃん
今日の４時って言ったよね？
It told you it's at 4:00 today, right, Hachi?
It's already 3:30 over there.
そっちは もう３時半…
- I've got bigger things
to worry about!
そんな場合じゃねえって
ああ ああ… ぐう
（課長）いやあ でも
先方には話しちゃったからさあ
But I've already spoken
to the other party, and...
Look, I'm trying to
tell you that...
だから… おおっ？
忍法 電話ボックスの舞！
Ninpo, Flying Phonebox
Technique!
（タナベ）うそ！
No way!
（ハチマキ）どわあ
（タナベ）ええっ
（サリバン）
遅いですな 星野(ほしの)さんは
Hoshino-san sure is late...
（仲人）今日 月に着くって
言ってましたから―
They said that he would be arriving
on the moon today, so it's possible that
his flight was delayed.
便が遅れてるのかも
うん… お水 もう１杯ください！
Another water over here,
please!
カーッ 俺は４時には ホテルに
いなきゃいけないっつうのに～
Damn it, I need to be
at the hotel by four!
超絶忍法 七転八倒
Transcendent ninpo!
Tossing in Agony Technique!
（忍者たち）横綱万歳！
Yokozuna, banzai!
（三次･小源太）いよお
（ハチマキ）いいっ…
What the hell are
you people thinking?!
何 考えてんだ！
（一同）おお～！
（忍者たちの拍手）
Roast pork noodles!
（ハチマキ）チャーシュー麺！
いっ がっ うぐっ
いいかげんにしろよ お前ら！
Give it a rest,
you lunatics!
（小源太）風馬 まんじ固め
Wind demon,
closed gammadion!
（紅右近）玉(たま)屋
Tamaya!
（幻之丞）あっぱれ
（タナベ）えっ？
Bravo!
（忍者たち）ラリホー
Rally ho!
（チュン）
あやっ あの男がいない
Huh? That man
is gone!
どこへ消えうせた？
Where has he
disappeared to?!
Behind us!
後ろだ！
先輩！
Senpai!
I've had about enough
of you guys!
（ハチマキ）
てめえら もう許さん！
Secret arts!
奥義！
The white rabbit!
因幡(いなば) の―
Of!
し ろ う さ ぎ
I-n-a-b-a!
（拍手）
I'm outta here,
Tanabe.
あっ
（ハチマキ）いっ げえっ この！
Aw, man!
You little...
（忍者たち）やられた
You got us!
ああ？
Truly, the way of the warrior
is to be found in death...
武士道とは 死ぬことと見つけたり
ぬふっ
（ハチマキ）かあ あ…
But aren't the people in
Debris Section a little rowdy?
でも デブリ課の人って
騒がしくありません？
（チェンシン）アハッ
He may not look it, but ever since Hachi met
that new girl, Tanabe, he's really settled down.
あれでも タナベさんっていう
後輩ができて ハチとかも―
随分おとなしくなった…
（ハチマキ）キエーッ！
胡蝶(こちょう)の舞！
Flying butterfly!
Impertinent swine!
（小源太）おのれ ちょこざいな
（幻之丞）いざ尋常に
Fight us...
...fair and square!
（紅右近）勝負勝負
（三次）猿飛
Flying monkey!
Ready... fight!
（太郎坊）はっけよい
（地雷也）ゲロヨン
Ribbit!
（チュン）アチョー アチョー
ニッ アチョー！
Senpai!
Wait for me!
（タナベ）先輩 待ってくださいよ
えーっと…
（リュシー）はあ…
Um...
（ハチマキ）いやあーっ！
ふんんんっ くっ ふっ
アチャチャチャチャチャー！
（ハチマキ）ていっ
（太郎坊）むっつり
Backwards pivot throw!
ほっ
（ハチマキ）ぎゃっ
のこった
He's still fighting?
ならば 我が妖術で
In that case, I'll use
my black magic to...
（紅右近）
待て待て 次 俺の番だろ
Wait, wait!
It's my turn next!
Hey, would this be a good time
to use my smoke bombs?
ねえねえ
煙玉 使ってもいいかな？
（地雷也）
あれやってみようよ 忍者まんだら
No, let's try out
the Ninja Mandala!
（ハチマキ）どわあーっ！
秘奥義 大玉 あっ 転がしぃ
Secret arts!
Giant Rolling Ball!
That's some serious ninpo!
- Show us, show us!
（忍者たち）ありゃ 大技だ
Senpai, what the heck
are you thinking?!
先輩 何 考えてんですか？
（ブザー音）
あれ？ ん？
Huh?
（ハチマキ）どわっ ぎゃああーっ
（忍者たち）うわあっ
Senpai!
（タナベ）せんぱーい！
返事してください 先輩！
Say something, Senpai!
んっ うっ んっ んっ
んっ ぐっ うっ…
はっ… あ？
A one and a two
and a heave-ho!
（一同）
えんや こら どっこいしょ
Senpai!
先輩！
Are you alive?
生きてますか？
（ハチマキ）あ ああ… あ？
We're sorry.
（地雷也）すみません
The landlord said that
a Japanese person was coming...
大家さんから
日本人が来るって聞いたら―
I guess we got a little
too enthusiastic.
なんだか うれしくなっちゃって
Plus, you were wearing the
hachimaki headband of a ninja.
（小源太）
忍者のしるしのハチマキもしてるし
（太郎坊）
本場の人に見てもらいたくて つい
We wanted a real, live Japanese
person to see our moves.
どうですか？ 僕らの忍法
What did you think
of our ninpo?
日本人は みんな ブラックベルトを
持ってるんですよね
Everybody in Japan
has a black belt, right?
Once you reach the upper ninja ranks,
you get to marry a geisha girl, right?
上忍になると ゲイシャガールと
結婚できるんでしょ？
Where did you people
learn this garbage?
それ 誰に教わった？
Miss Kunoichi.
（小源太）ミス くのいち
（タナベ）ん？
We bid you welcome to
Maison de Yashiki.
メゾン･ド･ヤシキにようこそ
えっ…
（太郎坊）あそこに住むんでしょ？
You're living there, right?
I'm Crimson Ukon, room 3.
My real name is Macleod.
俺 ３号室の紅右近
本名はマクロード
Gennojo the Missionary. Room 3.
Sanji the Monkey. Room 3.
猿の三次 ３号室
Jiraiya of Hida. Room 3.
飛騨の地雷也 ３号室
３号室のドラゴン･チュン
Dragon Chung! Room 3!
皆さん ３号室？
You all live
in room 3?
（ハチマキ）うう…
（現場監督）こらあ！
（ハチマキ･タナベ）あっ？
Hey!
You snuck in here again,
didn't you?!
（現場監督）
お前ら また勝手に入りやがって！
（小源太）すいませーん
（地雷也）先日はどうも
We're sorry!
- Thanks for the work
the other day!
Feel free to
call on us again!
（幻之丞）
よかったら また使ってくださーい
（現場監督）
ヘッ 人手は足りてるよ！
I have all the people I need!
（三次）そっすか すいません
Oh, you do?
Sorry!
Sorry to bother you!
（チュン）お邪魔しました
（紅右近）こないだ
工事の仕事 手伝ったんだ
We helped out on a construction
job there a while ago.
（三次）
ほら 俺たち忍法 使えるだろ？
We can use ninja ninpo techniques, right?
That's why they came to us.
だから頼まれてさ
（タナベ）へえ
（店主）うん？ あんたら！
Hey, you! You better do something
about your cleaning bill!
たまってるツケ
どうなってるんだい？
We're sorry, Onee-san.
We'll pay you next month for sure.
ああ 悪いね おねえさん
来月には必ず
払ってくれないと
預かってる服も渡せないよ
If you don't pay up, you're not getting back
the clothes you left here!
（小源太）
ええっ 頼むよ 明日も面接で
Have a heart! I have another
job interview tomorrow!
You'll just get turned down again, right?
Suit or no suit, it'll end the same way!
（店主）
どうせ また落ちるんだろ？
スーツなんか
着ても着なくても同じさ
その格好で
行けばいいじゃないか！
So you can just go there
dressed in that getup!
（男性）
お前ら また忍者ごっこか？
Playing ninja again,
are we?
Hurry up and
get a job!
早く 仕事 見つけろよ
（一同）うっ うう…
（タナベ）ん？
（ハチマキ）ん…
This is an announcement from the municipal
offices of Mare Tranquilitatis City.
（アナウンス）静(しず)かの海(うみ)市
市政本部よりお知らせします
Beginning at 2100 hours today,
there will be...
本日 21時より…
すいません 遅くなりました
I'm sorry I'm so late.
ああ そうそう
うちの課長から これ…
Oh, right. I have something
from my section chief.
Here.
Oh, my! This is a "get-acquainted gift"
from Hoshino-san!
（仲人）まあ ほら これ
星野さんから
お近づきのしるしにって
開けてみて 開けてみて
Open it, open it!
あっ いや その…
Um, I wasn't
the one who...
（チッタ）きれい！
ありがとうございます
It's beautiful!
Thank you so much!
Um, I didn't...
いや 俺は…
（仲人）星野さん
Hoshino-san,
this is Citta Sullivan-san.
こちら チッタ･サリバンさん
はあ
Uh...
（仲人）転勤するお父さんについて
わざわざ月まで来たの
She came all the way to the moon with
her father when he was transferred here.
You seldom see such devotion
in children these days, do you?
今どき珍しい
親孝行な娘さんでしょう？
Right...
（ハチマキ）ええ
（仲人）こちら 星野八郎太(はちろうた)さん
テクノーラ社にお勤めなの
This is Hoshino Hachirota-san.
He works for Technora.
My, that's a large company.
I bet you have a steady income.
（サリバン）いやあ 大企業だ
生活も安定している
よろしく頼むよ 星野君
It's a pleasure to meet you, Hoshino-kun.
Now, then, we should give these two
youngsters some time to themselves!
じゃあ あとは
若い人同士ということで
（ハチマキ）でえっ おい！
Wha...? Hey!
Do you like roses?
Now that you mention it, I hear that they have...
a Chinese-style garden on the first floor.
いや あの…
Wait, um...
私 日本って 大好きなんです
I love everything
about Japan.
Huh?
えっ…
いや だから…
Look, I think
there's been a...
I'm sorry, I'll only
be a minute.
すいません ちょっと失礼します
Hey, uh...
（ハチマキ）
えっ あの… なんで？
What's going on?
Honestly, thank you for finding
such an excellent match!
（サリバン）いやあ ほんとに
いい話をありがとうございます
Think nothing of it. Your daughter
is quite lovely, after all.
（仲人）
いいえ いいえ 娘さんもきれい…
Those two are just
getting started!
（チッタ）
ウーン 絶対ものにしなくっちゃ！
I'm gonna make
this one work!
（タナベ）
本当に皆さん ３号室なんですね
You really do all live
here in room 3, huh?
（小源太）お恥ずかしい話
我々は失業者なんですよ
It's embarrassing to say it,
but we're all unemployed.
はあ
Oh...
We don't have jobs, so we
have a lot of spare time.
（小源太）仕事がないから
毎日 毎日 退屈でね
That's how we ended up getting
hooked on ninja movies.
そのとき
忍者ムービーにハマりまして
（地雷也）重力６分の１だから
できちゃうんですよ 忍法
The gravity is 1/6 G, so you
can do ninpo techniques here!
（三次）
あっ でも最初は働いてたんだよ
Oh! We did have jobs
at first, though.
We were brought here by a businessman who
asked us if we wanted helium-3 extraction jobs.
月でヘリウム３の採取を
やらないかって誘われたんです
いい稼ぎになるからって
平たく言えば出稼ぎです
He said the money
would be good.
To make a long story short,
we left home to find work.
それで月に
And that's what brought you
to the moon...
おいどんは
３人目の子供 生まれた
My wife and I had just had
our third baby...
え？
（チュン）事業に失敗しまして
My business had gone belly up.
I had put up collateral for a friend.
友達の保証人になって
I needed the money.
お金 必要だったんですよ
I had such big dreams...
夢は大きかったなあ
But the businessman I told you about
skipped town with our pay.
しかし
口を利いてくれた業者が―
私たちの給料と一緒に
ドロンしまして―
あおりを食らって 我々はく…
We took the fall for it,
and they fired us.
また探せばいいじゃないですか
Then you should look
for new ones!
Like ilmenite mining
or working the drydocks!
イルメナイト掘りとか
造船ドックとか
But you need worker visas
to get a job, right?
でも 働くには
就業ビザが必要でしょう？
俺たちって
観光ビザで入ってるから
We came here on tourist visas.
（タナベ）え？
It was our own fault for letting that
businessman handle our visas, too...
我々が悪いんですよ
（地雷也）地球に帰る金もなくて
We don't have the money
to go back to Earth...
（三次）アルバイトで
なんとか食いつないでるんだ
We manage to keep ourselves fed
by taking odd jobs...
（タナベ）ああ…
い… いやあ やっぱ―
H-Hey, having a kunoichi here really
brightens things up, doesn't it?
Note: 'kunoichi' means female ninja.
くのいちがいると
パッと華やぐよね
うん くのいち いいよね
Yeah, kunoichis
are the best.
It's dull with nobody
but guys around.
男だけだと地味だし
A name! We have to think of
a name for Tanabe-san!
名前 名前 考えなくっちゃ
タナベさんの
Let's make it something flowery
this time!
今度は明るいやつにしよう
“シロガネ”とか“胡蝶”とか
Like Shirogane or Kocho.
"This time"?
今度？
Yeah! We used to...
ああ 前は あっ…
My wife used to act
as our kunoichi.
（小源太）以前は私の妻が
くのいちをやってくれてたんです
いや もう妻ではありませんね
No, I suppose she isn't
my wife anymore...
出ていきました
She left me.
I can't say
that I blame her.
しかたないですよ
ホレた女一人
養えないんですから
After all, I can't even support
the woman I love.
（一同）うう…
（サイレン）
An emergency has been declared
in Level E, West Sector 4.
（サイレン）
（タナベ）パトカー？
A police car?
（サイレン）
Isn't that an ambulance?
（三次）救急車じゃない？
An evacuation advisory has been issued
for the East and North sectors.
（アナウンス）
東地区および北地区に―
No, it's the fire department train.
いや 消防列車だ
避難勧告が
発令されています
（男性）ただでさえ
最高層は暑いってのによ
Stand back!
It's dangerous!
（消防署員１）
下がってください 危険です
Hey, do something about
those onlookers!
（消防署員２）
ほれ やじ馬どもをなんとかしろ！
They're verifying IDs
over at the tent!
（消防署員３）テントのほうで
身元の確認を行っています
（消防署員４）
道を空けてください
Clear the way!
（小源太）お義父(とう)さん？
（サリバン）ん？
Father?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
娘との離婚は成立したんだ
My daughter's divorce with you went through.
You have no business calling me "Father" now.
“お義父さん”と
呼ばれる筋合いはない
う… 仕事を見つけたら
考え直してくれる約束でしたよね
You promised that you'd reconsider
if I found a job, though, right?
I set up a
marriage meeting!
見合いしたんだよ！
I did it to make sure that she wouldn't get
involved with another piece of trash like you!
今度こそ お前みたいなクズに
引っ掛からないように
お見合い！？
マリッジミーティング…
A marriage meeting?!
She could've been happy if she hadn't
married the likes of you!
（サリバン）
お前みたいなのと結婚しなければ
幸せになれたんだ
ホテルで見合いなんて
しなくて済んだんだよ
Then we wouldn't have had
a marriage meeting at this hotel!
ううっ…
あっ まさか まだ あの中に
Wait... Are you telling me
that she's still in there?!
You lowlife!
You and your toys!
このクズが！
こんな おもちゃ
What good are you and your ninpo if they
can't even make one girl happy?!
女一人 幸せにできないで
何が忍法だ！
You! You! You pauper! You screwup!
この この この貧乏人
能無し 虫けら 穀潰し
You nobody! You loafer!
- Chieftain...
金も地位も仕事もなくて
その上 忍者だと？
You've got no money,
no social standing, and no job, and on top of all that,
you think you're a ninja?!
You think you can call yourself
a husband?!
そんなものが夫と呼べるか！
You lowlife! Lowlife! Lowlife!
このクズが クズが クズが！
ああっ…
（タナベ）愛があります
He has love!
（サリバン）ええっ…
Even if he's a ninja,
even if he's got no money, if he's got love,
it'll work out in the end!
（タナベ）たとえ忍者でも
お金がなくても―
愛があれば大丈夫です
No matter what kind of social standing or
fortune you've got, if you don't have love, you're a failure
as a husband!
どんなに地位や財産があったって
愛がなければ夫として失格ですよ
Who in the world
are you?
（サリバン）誰なんだ？ 君は
愛があれば
パンの耳だってごちそうです
If you've got love, even the ends
of a loaf of bread are a feast!
Even if she has
fancy dresses, it won't make her happy if a man she loves doesn't see her in them!
（タナベ）豪華なドレスだって―
愛する人に見てもらえなくちゃ
うれしくないでしょう？
（紅右近）頭領？
- Chieftain...?
愛する人に見てもらえなくちゃ
うれしくないでしょう？
俺一人でいい
I can do this
on my own.
俺たち クズじゃないですよね
We aren't lowlifes,
are we?
くのいちは １人より２人でしょう
Two kunoichis are better
than one, right?
見せてやりましょうよ 忍法の底力
Let's go show 'em!
Let's show 'em
what ninpo can do!
ヘッ バカどもが
You bunch of fools.
Why won't you understand!
Say something, Chieftain!
どうして
分かってあげないんですか
頭領さんも 何か言って…
あれ？
Huh?
（チッタ）ううっ んっ んあっ
Darn it, who the heck
cut the power?!
もう 電源 落としたの誰よ
厨房にあった
（チッタ）早く 早く
I found this
in the kitchen!
Hurry! Hurry!
キャーッ
Let's go. The place is already
filling up with smoke.
行くぞ もう かなり煙が回ってる
（チッタ）うっ… うん
Level E Control Room calling
all police cars on patrol...
（小源太）一本
（三次）有効
Full point!
Quarter point!
（紅右近）効果
（チュン）技あり
Eighth point!
Half point!
（幻之丞）場外
（地雷也）指導
Out of bounds!
Foul!
（消防署員）おっ？
頭領 ここは無理です
別の階段 探しましょう
Chieftain, this way's no good.
Let's look for another stairway.
（一同）うーん…
ええい やっ！
とおっ ほっ てあっ
（一同）おお！
（紅右近）俺たちも続くぞ！
（一同）おう！
Let's follow
his lead!
Yeah!
The scene of the fire is adjacent
to the redevelopment area,
（男性１）すげえ
Oh, wow!
Looks like that hotel had
second-rate firefighting equipment.
（男性２）あのホテル
防災装置 甘かったらしいぜ
...and with the upcoming maintenance work, the
advance of emergency vehicles is hampered...
ん？
（チッタ）んっ…
よせ！
駆け抜ける前に 煙に巻かれる
Forget it! The smoke would overpower us
before we could get through!
But there's smoke everywhere!
There's nowhere to go!
でも どこも煙でいっぱいで
もう行く所が…
（ハチマキ）あっ…
ああ…
（チッタ）何？
What is it?
ちゅう房に戻るぞ
（チッタ）ええ？
Back to the kitchen!
お面！
Point!
（チュン）胴 胴 胴
Face strike!
（幻之丞）小手 小手 小手…
（紅右近）のさぁ
Veranda!
Sliding door!
（地雷也）ふすま
Bamboo screens!
（三次）あれ～
なっ… うっ
（サリバン）娘が…
娘がまだ降りてきてないんだ
My daughter! My daughter
hasn't come down yet!
忍者もです！
Other ninjas!
（消防署員）
道を空けてください 道を空けて
Clear the way, please!
Clear the way!
（小源太）うっ ぐうっ
Chieftain!
頭領
（小源太）うっ 大丈夫だ
少し煙を吸っただけだ
I'm all right...
I inhaled a little smoke, that's all.
後ろも煙で塞がっちまったよ
The way back is blocked
with smoke, too...
Is this... Is this
the end for us?
ここまで…
ここまでなのか
あっ
（ハチマキ･チッタ）
ハァ フゥ ハァ フゥ…
（一同）ああっ
（ハチマキ･チッタ）
ハァ フゥ ハァ フゥ…
That's hot!
あっちい
（チッタ）ハァ フゥ…
おりん おりんか？
O-rin!
O-rin, is that you?!
小源太！
Kogenta?!
Huh? The ninjas?
What're you doing here?
（ハチマキ）
あれ？ 忍者？ どうして？
（小源太）
ハチマキさん あんたが妻を？
Hachimaki-san?
You saved my wife?
いや こいつのおかげだよ
過酸化石灰製剤
No, we have these
to thank.
A solution of
calcium peroxide.
要するに植物の肥料を水に入れると
酸素が発生するんだ
Basically, if we add it to the fertilized water
for the plants here, it generates oxygen.
ちょうどいい所に
電磁用のセラミック鍋もあったしな
We were lucky that they also had some
ceramic pots for their microwave, too.
Now that you mention it, Ai-chan did mention
that you were astronauts...
そういや
愛(あい)ちゃんが宇宙飛行士だって
Oh, I get it! They're like
homemade spacesuits.
そうか
お手製の宇宙服みたいな物か
All we need to do now is head back
the way you came in, and we should be able
to get out of here.
（ハチマキ）
あとは あんたらの来た道を戻れば
なんとか脱出できる
無理だよ この道は―
We can't. The way back is...
We can't go back that way now.
俺たちも戻れなくなったんだから
（ハチマキ）ええっ！？
So you're saying that there's
nowhere to run?!
じゃあ 逃げ場なしってこと？
What did you come
here for, then?!
あんたら 結局 何しに来たのよ！
いや 大丈夫だ
忍者に不可能はない！
No, we'll be fine!
Nothing is impossible for a ninja!
（一同）ええっ！？
あんたらプロだろ
とっとと娘を助けろ！
You people are professionals, aren't you?!
Get in there and save my daughter!
その服 貸してください
私が行きます
Give me your suit!
I'll go in, too!
その服 貸してください
私が行きます
（割れる音）
ああっ
（タナベ･サリバン）ええっ？
（一同）我ら 忍者８人衆！
We!
Are!
The Ninja Eight!
えっ？
（一同）んんっ
（消防署員）にん… じゃ？
Ninjas...?
You're kidding!
Even at 1/6 G, it's still...
もしかして―
いくら６分の１Ｇだからって
まさか…
They wouldn't!
風林火山
Wind, woods,
fire, mountain!
（一同）大化の改新
The Reforms of
the Taika Era!
満漢全席！
Chinese royal
full-course banquet!
やめてー！
Don't do it!
Ultimate secret technique!
最終奥義
霞忍法 大宇宙ムササビ変化(へんげ)
Mist ninpo! Form cosmic
flying squirrel!
（一同）ああっ
You've gotta be
kidding me...
んな バカな
いくら６分の１だからって
Even at 1/6 G,
they're still gonna...
忍者！
Ninjas!
Ninjas?
（女性１）忍者？
（男性１）忍者だって？
Did he say ninjas?
It's ninjas!
（男性２）忍者だ
（女性２）えっ？
Ninjas?
（男性３）忍者だ
（女性３）忍者…
（男性４）忍者だよ
It's ninjas!
（人々の歓声）
Ninja!
（一同）
忍者！ 忍者！ 忍者！ 忍者！
（ハチマキ）ハハハッ
忍者 アハハハッ
Ninja!
Boy, landings sure are tough,
aren't they?
（三次）
いやあ 着地って難しいんだね
（地雷也）地面に着いた途端
一気に体重がかかるんだもんな
Yeah, your weight hits you all
at once when you touch down...
What the hell is going on here?! Well?!
（ハチマキ）どういうことなんだよ
これは ああ？
だって ハッちゃん
If I had told you it was a marriage meeting,
would you have agreed to go, Hachi?
見合いって言ったら
受けてくれないでしょ？
Of course not! As if
I'd ever get married!
当たり前だ！ 誰が結婚なんて
うちの娘じゃ 不足だってのか？
Are you saying that my daughter's
not good enough for you?!
Father, I'll make her happy,
so you don't have to worry!
お義父さん
僕が彼女を幸せにしますから
だから あんたとは別れたの！
Get it straight!
We're divorced!
And a real ninja name
is something like "Saizou!"
What kind of name
is "Kogenta"?!
小源太なんて センスないんだから
Chief, how many months is the lease
on my apartment for?
課長 私のアパート
何か月契約なんですか？
When are you gonna
move in, Ai-chan?
愛ちゃん いつ越してくんの？
For now,
it's for two years.
取りあえず２年
礼金とか無駄になっちゃうからさ
The deposit would've gone
to waste, otherwise.
How about "Shooting Star Ai"?
“流れ星の愛”なんて どうかな？
（タナベ）あっ いや
くのいちは ちょっと…
Come on, I'm not
your kunoichi.
Do you have a paring knife
or something?
果物ナイフとか持ってない？
I have a throwing knife,
if that'll work.
くないなら持ってるけど
Hey, they said that those
aren't allowed in here!
あっ 持ち込み禁止って
言われてんのに
He's treating my daughter like dirt
just because she's a divorcee!
うちの娘がバツイチだからって
軽く見やがって
星野さんで
宇宙お見合い 49件目なのよ
Hoshino-san makes her 49th Space Marriage Meeting.
ええ？
The next one will be 50 even!
Let's do it next time!
（仲人）次なら ちょうど 50件目
次にしましょう 次に
おりんちゃん
（チッタ）うるさい
O-rin-chan~
Go away!
Ninpo Flying Pillow!
忍法 飛び枕！
Ninpo Flying Pillow Catch!
忍法 枕取り
（地雷也）枕返しの術
Ninpo Flying Pillow Return Technique!
（幻之丞）枕ホマミキサー
It's a bitter pillow
to swallow!
（チュン）お先 まっくら
Go pop a pillow!
また…
Here we go again...
（ハチマキ）はあ～あ
ぐうっ
ぐあっ くっ…
Ninpo is hereby
forbidden!
忍法は禁止だー 禁止！
It's banned!
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Extraterrestrial Girl
（ハチマキ）何だ？ これ
What's this?
（タナベ）
お見舞い リンゴです
A get-well gift. It's an apple.
（ハチマキ）俺たちは
地球から離れては―
We humans can't live
away from the Earth.
生きていけない
That's just the way it is
right now.
それが 今の現実だ
（ノノ）見てみたいな
ハチマキの海
I sure would like to see
your ocean, Hachimaki!
（ローランド）
全く 最近の若いのは―
I swear, kids nowadays
aren't worth their salt.
だらしないな
（ノノ）２人だと
なかなか終わんないの
With just two people, it takes
forever to finish a game.
俺を勝手に引退させるな
Don't you dare force me
to retire, you hear?!
（ノノ）どう？ ハチマキ
私の海
What do you think, Hachimaki?
This is my sea!